Fletcher School Records UA015
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Fletcher program theses, 1981 -- 2015; UA015.012; 286 Digital Object(s); 1 Volumes
  - Possibilities for Promoting Global Education in Japan, 2003; UA015.012.DO.00031; Ushida, Mayako
    Submitted in partial fulfillment of the degree Master of Arts in Law and Diplomacy at the Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy. Abstract: This paper investigates the possibilities for promoting Global Education (GE) in Japan. The first section attempts to gain a clear picture of GE in its international and Japanese contexts, its history and development, and its current practices. The obstacles to practicing GE in Japan are also examined. The second section considers the history and development of Education for International Understanding in its international context, as well as its history and practice in elementary, junior high, and high schools in Japan. Using interviews and the results of a survey that included 403 elementary, junior high, and high school level teachers in Japan, the third section examines the attitudes of teachers toward GE. The specific questions addressed in this section include the teachers' level of interest in GE issues, the classroom practice of GE and the reasons for this, the obstacles they face in practicing GE, and what kind of support they need. The paper concludes with recommendations for supporting teachers who have practiced GE and who want to practice GE and for GE promoters (e.g. Educational NGOs and other organizations) who can respond to some of the needs of teachers in teaching GE.
    MALD thesis; Education; International Education; Global Education
  - Unconventional Warfare as a Strategic Foreign Policy Tool: The Clinton Administration in Iraq and Afghanistan, 2004; UA015.012.DO.00032; Linnington, Abigail Thompson
    Submitted in partial fulfillment of the degree Master of Arts in Law and Diplomacy at the Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy. Abstract: While there is much literature on the operational and tactical military histories of U.S. Army Special Operations Forces (SOF) within security studies, little analysis exists of their primary mission, unconventional warfare (UW), and its implementation within a greater national security strategy. As the primary and founding mission of Army SOF, UW receives scant attention as a tool of American foreign policy that supports our national interest. This paper assesses U.S. unconventional warfare strategies employed during the 1990s in Iraq and Afghanistan and concludes that the United State ineffectively utilized UW as a strategic foreign policy tool in those two instances. It begins with a brief history of the development of UW doctrine, UW institutionalization within Army SOF, and the integration of SOF and the Central Intelligence Agency (CIA) for UW operations. The Clinton Administration's decision to implement UW with limited CIA assets is analyzed using prospect theory - a theory of decision-making under risk. The Administration's strategic objectives, while sound, were diminished by the president's lack of commitment to foreign policy, aversion to military solutions, and turbulent domestic politics. In the cases of Iraq and Afghanistan, the president considered four foreign policy options, settling on limited UW. Operating in the domain of losses, President Clinton pursued risk prone behavior by intervening within a hostile state despite risk averse tendencies resulting from past military failures. Ultimately, the decision to implement a limited, disjointed UW campaign outside a greater national strategy contributed to mission ineptitude. Ultimately, further comprehensive strategic analysis is necessary to ensure that the lessons learned from past U.S. successes and failures inform better use of UW assets as an asymmetrical fighting force against like-minded U.S. opponents.
    MALD thesis; Unconventional warfare; Special forces(Military science); Covert operations; International Security Studies; Southwest Asia and Islamic Civilization
  - Transatlantic Relations: A Study in Complementarity, 2004; UA015.012.DO.00033; Goh, Dominic
    Submitted in partial fulfillment of the degree Master of Arts in Law and Diplomacy at the Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy. Abstract: Many commentators and policy makers have referred to the complementary nature of transatlantic relations. This paper examines the concept of complementarity in more detail and demonstrates that complementarity can be viewed on four levels: 1. Interpersonal complementarity: Psychological studies have shown that people react to behavioural stimuli in certain fixed ways. For example, friendly behaviour evokes friendliness, and hostility begets hostility. This Interpersonal Principle of Complementarity can be applied to the transatlantic relationship to demonstrate the US needs to treat Europe as an equal if it wants to obtain European assistance. 2. Power-Law complementarity: The US, as the world's leading democracy, needs international legitimacy to act militarily. By working closely with Europe, the US is more likely to find that its actions are viewed as legitimate. 3. Supplemental complementarity: This is what most commentators refer to when they speak of complementarity. The issue is how the US and EU can cooperate by bringing their respective strengths into a particular operation. In most cases, the US will take the lead in the military operation, while the EU will take the lead in the peacekeeping and civil reconstruction phase. 4. Oppositional complementarity: Opposition is not usually thought of when speaking of complementarity. Nevertheless, complementarity can encompass oppositional as well as supplemental relationships. In the transatlantic context, it is important to manage the relationship such that cooperation is maximised, while opposition is minimised. After setting out the conceptual framework, the paper considers several cases since the end of the Cold War to show how the framework might work in practice. The cases considered are Bosnia, Kosovo, the Middle East Peace Process, Afghanistan, and Iraq. The cases demonstrate the validity of the above framework and the continued relevance of NATO as the primary vehicle for promoting transatlantic complementarity. However, as NATO does not include the EU in its formal structures, the paper concludes by showing that there is a growing need for an institutional mechanism to bring together the three key elements of the transatlantic relationship-- the US, the EU and NATO.
    MALD thesis; Comparative and Developmental Political Analysis; International Security Studies; International Relations; Transatlantic; NATO; European Union; complementarity
  - Ubudehe and the Kecamatan Development Projects: Case Study and Comparative Analysis, 2004; UA015.012.DO.00034; Dunbar, Judith Scott
    Submitted in partial fulfillment of the degree Master of Arts in Law and Diplomacy at the Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy. Abstract: Donors have developed a number of different approaches to support decentralization, including grant programs for public infrastructure and community development planning. Such programs are designed both to build local officials capacity to govern, and to build the community's capacity to set its own priorities and design its own development solutions. Two such programs are the Ubudehe process in Rwanda, and the World Bank Kecamatan Development Projects (KDP I, II and III) in Indonesia. Both programs provide grants to local level government to help support a government-sponsored decentralization effort, and to help build community capacity through participatory development planning. The paper finds that while the programs have different contexts, funding and mandates, they faced similar challenges. This paper analyzes these programs based on project documents and evaluations. Costs and benefits of each program are examined in light of the major obstacles they face. The final section of the paper compares the two programs, and draws out the major lessons learned, including differences in context, mandate, financial structure, funding and anti-corruption strategies.
    MALD thesis; Comparative and Developmental Political Analysis; Development Economics; Grant programs; decentralization
  - The Hispanic Paradigm: to acculturate or not to acculturate?, 2004; UA015.012.DO.00035; Comenge, Alberto
    Submitted in partial fulfillment of the degree Master of Arts in Law and Diplomacy at the Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy. Abstract: The aim of this thesis is to investigate the process of acculturation of minorities into American mainstream culture, providing a framework that analyzes the most important factors that influence the process of acculturation. The minority analyzed throughout the research is the Hispanic community because of two main reasons. The first reason is the controversial arguments published recently by Samuel Huntington that alert that Hispanics, especially Mexican-Hispanics, do not acculturate into American culture, which could potentially fragment U.S. culture for the first time in its history. The second reason why I have decided to prove these factors of acculturation in Hispanics is because it is the largest minority in the United States since 2002, with the high probability of becoming the second largest concentration of Hispanics in the world in less than ten years and the eighth largest purchasing economy in the world, ahead of Canada by 2007. Once understood all the factors and differences that affect the acculturation of Hispanics, the ending chapter will be dedicated to understand the marketing implications derived from the emergence of this minority, understanding how to segment most efficiently and analyzing within each segment different consumer behaviors, media consumption and more efficient ways to target and understand this important and growing segment of the U.S. population.
    MALD thesis; International Business Relations; International Information and Communication; Hispanics; acculturation; assimilation
  - AIDS in Africa: A Security Threat?, 2004; UA015.012.DO.00036; White, Elizabeth Hadley
    Submitted in partial fulfillment of the degree Master of Arts in Law and Diplomacy at the Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy. Abstract: Can a disease constitute a security threat? In 2000 the National Intelligence Council first identified HIV/AIDS as a threat, not only to Africa, but to the United States. This paper explores this shift from national to human security concerns and analyzes how AIDS is capable of severely impacting state structures in Africa. If AIDS is not contained in Africa in the near future, the real possibility exists of state instability and failure occurring throughout the continent. This will affect the United States on many fronts, including its national security interests.
    MALD thesis; International Security Studies; HIV; AIDS; Security; Threat; Public Health
  - Rice Trade Issues between Japan and Thailand, 2004; UA015.012.DO.00037; Chantadansuwan, Sittikorn
    Submitted in partial fulfillment of the degree Master of Arts in Law and Diplomacy at the Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy. Abstract: Thailand, the largest rice exporting country in the world, had expected new rice market opportunities when the Japanese market was liberalized by the Uruguay Round. However, Thailand was unsatisfied with the Japanese rice market access, claiming that the Japanese rice import regime lacked transparency. In particular, Thailand argued that Japan used de facto country specific quotas to determine the in-tariff quota in its minimum access regime. The alleged "country specific quota" prevented Thailand from attaining a market share in the Japanese import rice market, as it should have been able to do. Is the allegation above warranted? Was the Japanese rice import regime in 2001 -- the so-called minimum access regime -- legal under the World Trade Organization (WTO) law? This thesis purports to examine this claim under the WTO legal order of which Japan and Thailand are Members.
    MALD thesis; International Trade and Commerical Policies; International Business and Economic Law; Rice; Trade; SBS; World Trade Organization
  - Internatioinal Aid and Democratic Building Process: Cambodia, 2004; UA015.012.DO.00038; Van, Tooch
    Submitted in partial fulfillment of the degree Master of Arts in Law and Diplomacy at the Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy. Abstract: None available.
    MALD thesis; Comparative and Developmental Political Analysis; Development Economics
  - Microfinance and Conflict: Toward a Conflict-Sensitive Approach, 2004; UA015.012.DO.00039; Heen, Stacy
    Submitted in partial fulfillment of the degree Master of Arts in Law and Diplomacy at the Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy. Abstract: In a 1996 report, Geetha Nagarajan remarked that "studies on the consequences of conflicts on the development of financial markets and on issues concerning the design and implementation of financial programmes in post-conflict countries are very limited. In short, issues regarding the development of financial institutions in conflict-affected countries are emerging topics of interest on which there has been little research and even less published." An increasing amount of research on how to do microfinance in post-armed conflict environments has occurred in the ensuing eight years, though little writing links this work to the broader discourse on the development-conflict nexus and the growing international momentum toward conflict-sensitive programming. Moreover, the predominant focus among microfinance researchers is on how conflict impacts microfinance; no writing seems to address how microfinance impacts conflict. This thesis attempts to bridge this gap by proposing three ways in which the mobilization of microcredit could, in itself, dampen conflict tensions and reduce the potential for escalation toward open violence. These three mechanisms, termed "direct", "indirect", and "process" mitigation, evolved out of field research instigated at the request of a small credit union in rural Cameroon to examine the links between credit and conflict. These mechanisms, or typology, form the conceptual heart of this thesis.
    MALD thesis; Development Economics; International Negotiation and Conflict Resolution; Microfinance.; microcredit; Conflict; conflict sensitivity; Development
  - The Environmental, Technical and Economic Implications of the White Spot Syndrome Virus on Latin American Shrimp Farming, 2004; UA015.012.DO.00040; McClennen, Caleb
    Submitted in partial fulfillment of the degree Master of Arts in Law and Diplomacy at the Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy. Abstract: In the past twenty years, export oriented shrimp farming in Latin America and throughout the world has boomed, diversifying national trade, while providing a much needed boost to poor coastal economies. The industry is praised from within, while emphatically lambasted by many international activists who cite the destruction of mangrove ecosystems and coastal fisheries, gains in the hands of a few and politically corrupt structures guiding an ultimately unsustainable extractive industry. In 1999, the White Spot Syndrome Virus (WSSV) epizootic quickly spread through nine Pacific coast Latin American countries, costing billions of dollars in regional export earnings of which most of the economies have yet to recover. However, in all countries, university scientists, farm owners and technicians, NGOs and international development agencies are working on solution to survive with WSSV. This investigation first seeks to account for the short term devastation of the disease, and then examines its long-term effects on the sustainability, both ecologically and economically, of the Latin American shrimp farming industry. Sustainability is examined by analysis of the economic, technical, legal and environmental changes that can be attributed to the disease shock. Data and research was gathered through government and NGO reports and analysis, industry publications and numerous interviews through coastal Peru, Ecuador and Mexico. The experiences of these three countries are explored as representative case studies of the region. It is concluded that on average the disease has left the industry, though crippled, an ecologically more sound, legally more controlled, politically more integrated and overall more sustainable structure than in the past. The massive profits wrought from the low control and hastily planned boom days of the 1980s and 1990s are those of the past. The WSSV has accelerated existing industry trends towards efficiency and scientific understanding to increase profits and survive future challenges while simultaneously decreasing negative externalities.
    MALD thesis; International Environment and Resource Policy; Development Economics; Shrimp Farming; Sustainable Development; Environmental Policy
  - Legal reform and economic development in Vietnam and China: a comparative analysis, 2004; UA015.012.DO.00041; Day, Adam C
    Submitted in partial fulfillment of the degree Master of Arts in Law and Diplomacy at the Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy. Abstract: none available.
    MALD thesis; Law Development; Comparative and Developmental Political Analysis; legal reform; Development; role of lawyers; judiciary
  - An Analysis of the Treatment of Asset Securitization under the Proposed Basel II Accord and the U.S. Banking Agencies' Advance Notice of Proposed Rulemaking (ANPR), 2004; UA015.012.DO.00042; Rinne, April K
    MALD thesis; Asset securitization; International Capital Requirements; Basel Accord
  - Future Relations between Kuwait Petroleum Corporation and the International Oil Companies: Success or Failure?, 2004; UA015.012.DO.00043; Abulhasan, Arwa Mohammad
    Submitted in partial fulfillment of the degree Master of Arts in Law and Diplomacy at the Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy. Abstract: Around the world, the relationship between International Oil Companies (IOCs) and oil producing countries ranges from animosity to cooperation; the relationship with Kuwait lies somewhere between these two extremes. Currently, the Kuwait Petroleum Corporation (KPC) is looking towards cooperation with the IOCs, while the Kuwaiti Parliament is wary of allowing IOC participation in Kuwait's only industry. Is there any room for agreement in this economic venture that involves Kuwait's national wealth and sovereignty, and if so, what type of agreement will emerge with the IOCs, KPC, and the Kuwaiti Parliament as players?
    MALD thesis; International Capital Requirements; International Business; International Negotiation and Conflict Resolution; Petroleum; International Oil Compainies; Abu Dhabi
  - The EU and US Trade Authorities: A Comparison, 2004; UA015.012.DO.00044; Amadei, Paola
    Submitted in partial fulfillment of the degree Master of Arts in Law and Diplomacy at the Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy. Abstract: Comparison of the EU and US trade authorities and review of the possible effects of their respective structures on their capacity to negotiate and bargain in the WTO framework.
    MALD thesis; ITCP; Trade; International Negotiations
  - When Dirty Money Turns Deadly: Why The Global Anti-Money Laundering Regime is Ill-Equipped to Deal With the War on Terrorism, and What To Do About It, 2004; UA015.012.DO.00045; Hasib, S. Waqar
    Submitted in partial fulfillment of the degree Master of Arts in Law and Diplomacy at the Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy. Abstract: One of the reasons that law enforcement agencies have been frustrated in their attempts to curb the flow of terrorist finances is that they are using old weapons to fight a new war. The framework of multilateral agreements, financial industry regulations, and domestic laws around the world that tackle money laundering were written largely during the 1980s to fight the War on Drugs, but are ill-equipped to fight the War on Terrorism. This paper explores the origins and characteristics of the global anti-money laundering regime, and why al Qaeda has been able to exploit numerous weaknesses in that regime. This paper also proposes a set of recommendations that law enforcement agencies and financial institutions should adopt, in order to adapt to the new threats posed to the global anti-money laundering regime by terrorist financing.
    MALD thesis; International Business and Economic Law; International Security Studies; Terrorist Financing; Money Laundering; Global Anti-Money Laundering Regime
  - Replacing Narco-usurers with Micro-lenders: Agricultural Finance Component of Opium Substitution Programs in Afghanistan, 2004; UA015.012.DO.00046; Anand, Bhuvana
    Submitted in partial fulfillment of the degree Master of Arts in Law and Diplomacy at the Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy. Abstract: Most of the focus in the opium substitution and eradication effort in Afghanistan since the fall of the Taliban has been on the development of alternative crops and enforcement of the ban issued by the interim administration. Program managers and researchers are focusing on the price dynamic influencing farmers decisions to cultivate opium, while underemphasizing the credit arrangements developed by narco-traders to incentivize opium cultivation. In the absence of access to other credit sources, small farmers find it especially difficult to resist the possibility of obtaining advances from narco-usurers for the opium crop before planting season. This paper argues that in the absence of effective control on factors influencing demand and prices for opium, the interim administration, NGOs, and donors should focus their attention on factors that influence farmers' decisions to cultivate poppy. Primary among these factors is the availability of credit, since is integral to coping strategies especially for smaller households. Providing alternative agricultural financing mechanisms and programs can be one of the strategies employed by international organizations and NGO's to divert production away from opium, especially in newer opium-growing regions. Designing these programs involves understanding of best practices in agricultural financing, Islamic financing, and administrative constraints in the Afghan environment. This paper analyses the opium credit- relationship that narco-usurers and traders have developed by exploiting the asset insecurity of Afghan households in sustaining the cultivation of opium. In response this paper recommends that agricultural micro-financing programs can play an important role in providing incentives to farmers to switch to crops other than opium, especially in the newer opium growing provinces. It finally makes recommendations about design choices, products, and administrative concerns that organizations can use while outlining their strategy.
    MALD thesis; Development Economics; Microfinance.; Crop substitution; Opium; Agricultural Credit; Agricultural Finance; Agriculture
  - Carbon Sequestration and its Potential as a Market Mechanism Tool for Sustainable Development, 2004; UA015.012.DO.00047; Minott, Nichola Diane
    Submitted in partial fulfillment of the degree Master of Arts in Law and Diplomacy at the Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy. Abstract: This thesis discusses the viability of carbon sequestration as a market mechanism tool for promoting environmental preservation, biodiversity and sustainable development. Specifically how forest based carbon sequestration projects can be utilized as a viable method of income generation. Bolivia and specifically the Noel Kempff Climate Action Plan will be used as a case study.
    MALD thesis; International Environment and Resource Policy; Carbon Sequestration; Sustainable Development; Kyoto Protocol